Thomas E. Kendig

48001 Leontine Court Fremont, CA 94539 (510) 657-2579 tom.kendig@kendig.net

ATE Applications and Customer Support Specialist

Applications engineer and software engineer in ATE. Support could be customer specific as in getting a test system into production use or across all customers as in a communications dll for EG probers used product wide.

Software responsibility included developing and maintaining a dynamically loadable library (.dll) under Microsoft .Net and a shared object (.so) under UNIX. With over 100K lines of code, this project was ported across four computer operating systems.

Often project oriented customer and third party vendor meetings were required and sometimes production monitoring data reports for customers were provided. The success of the software project depended on the extensive documentation (Frame/HTML) and ftp site distribution to world wide customers.

Software OS and Tools

.Net/Visual Studio/Codecenter Windows XP/NT
SourceSafe/make/ClearCase/SCCS UNIX/Solaris/SunOS
Framemaker/PDF DNS/NFS
Serial (RS232), IEEE488 (GPIB) communications
National Instruments GPIB analyzer UNIX system administration
Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point) Oracle

Computer Languages

C/C++ PASCAL bourne/csh shell scripts SQL/RPL LISP Modula-2, PL/1, FORTRAN

Engineering Applications

Communications Driver development

Real-Time Programming

Data processing (ASCII & STDF)

Software Test Procedures

VLSI Pattern Conversion

Circuit Testing

VLSI testing

Semiconductor Processing

Thomas E. Kendig

48001 Leontine Ct Fremont, CA 94539 (510) 657-2579 tom.kendig@kendig.net

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineer – Credence Systems Corp., Fremont, CA 1991-1992 & 1996-2005

- From coding through the build, archive and distribution process, maintained about 30 intelligent prober and handler communications drivers for Credence testers.
- Created a 150 page document describing the prober and handler communications and customer installation and usage.
- Improve production throughput up to 100% through monitored production floor performance on Credence manufactured ATE testers.
- Worldwide customer assistance in automation software install and test on their production test floor.
- Supplied simple parallel (TTL) cable implementations, design and debug for test floor prober and handler production automation.
- Ported a Graphical User Interface from a SUN 3 based architecture to a SPARC architecture. This included resolving porting problems such as data structure incompatibility in RPC packets and SunView programming errors.
- Improved a custom software build process that made extensive and unusual use of the utilities make and SCCS.

Customer Support Engineer – TeamOne Systems Inc., Sunnyvale, CA 1992-1994

- Provided 800 number customer support for configuration management software. TeamOne's system is a kernel based file system. Support entails knowing UNIX file systems, NFS and system administration.
- Developed call tracking software package facilitating call follow up and producing statistical measurements on incoming call servicing.

Applications Engineer – Teradyne Inc., Sunnyvale, CA

1989-1991

- Provided post sales support for the Semiconductor CIM Division FIRMS product line. This included integrating information from VLSI test systems into an Oracle data base for later RS/1 analysis.
- Taught the training classes for the Teradyne configured data base and graphics tools. Rewrote into Framemaker the User's and Manager's training course material.

EDUCATION

Carnegie-Mellon University, PGH, PA

BS in Mathematics, emphasis in CS and EE